Guide to the WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization) Records TAM.162
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Women's Action Coalition (WAC), 1992 (Box 4)
- Women Against Racism and Rape in Out Rage (WARRIOR), 1991 (Box 4)
- Women's Health Education Project, 1994 (Box 4)
- Women's Health Summit, 1993 (Box 4)
- Women's Rights Organizations, undated (Box 4)
- Youth Education Life Line (YELL), undated (Box 4)
- WHAM V-01 (VHS) Comer, Stop the Church & KCET L.A.; Discussion from Ch. 13/NY, 1.5 hours, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-02 (VHS) Sampler, This is NOT a Federal Reserve & Legal Selects (Injunction, prior arrests), September 6, 1990 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-03 (High 8) Abortion & Parental Consent, May 19, 1990 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-04 (VHS-C) Resisting Racism, 1st session, Tape 1, Setting ground rules for safe discussion, March 20, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-05 (VHS-C) Resisting Racism, 1st session, Tape 2, Small group discussion "How racism makes me feel", March 20, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-06 (VHS-C) Resisting Racism, 1st session, Tape 3, Small group feedback to larger group, homework, wrapup, March 20, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-07 (VHS-C) 2nd session, 1st tape, Thoughts on last session, homework, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-08 (VHS-C) 2nd session, 2nd tape, Where the power is, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-09 (VHS-C) 2nd session, 3rd tape, small group, What is Your race, ethnic background, sexual orientation, economic status, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-10 (VHS-C) 2nd session, 4th tape, (contd) small group, report back of small groups, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-11 (VHS-C) 2nd session, 5th tape (contd) report backs, wrap up, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-12 (VHS-C) Session 3, Tape 1, April 3, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-13 (VHS-C) Session 3, Tape 2, April 3, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-14 (VHS-C) Session 3, Tape 3, small groups, report back, April 3, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-15 (VHS-C) Session 3, Tape 4, April 3, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-16 (VHS-C) Session 4, Tape 1 personal journey as activist, April 10, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-17 (VHS-C) Session 4, Tape 2, April 10, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-18 (VHS-C) Session 4, Tape 3, April 10, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-19 (VHS-C) Session 4, Tape 4, report back to group, April 10, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-20 (VHS-C) Family of Choice, Intro Session 5, Tape 1, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-21 (VHS-C) Session 5, Tape 2, small group, family of choice, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-22 (VHS-C) Session 5, Tape 3, report back to larger group and small group discussion, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-23 (VHS-C) Session 5, Tape 4, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-24 (VHS-C) Session 5, Tape 5, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-25 (VHS-C) Session 6, Tape 1, Intro, discussion re March on Wash., WHAM! Organizational Setup, May 31, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-26 (VHS-C) Session 6, Tape 2, 1st (sexuality in WHAM!), May 31, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-27 (VHS-C) Session 6, Tape 3, 2nd fishbowl, beginning of Small group discussion, May 31, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-28 (VHS-C) Session 6, Tape 4, small group feedback to fishbowls/report back, May 31, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-29 (VHS-C) Session 6, Tape 5, May 31, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-30 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 1, May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-31 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 2, May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-32 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 3, May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-33 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 4, May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-34 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 5, May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-35 (VHS-C) Session 7, Tape 6 [or tape 5?], May 8, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-36 (VHS-C) Last session, Tape 1, May 21, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-37 (VHS-C) Last session, Tape 2, May 21, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-38 (VHS) [published video] In Your Face with Amazing Grace: The Vatican is Burning, The Church Ladies for Choice, produced by Lake of Fire Productions, 1993 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-39 (VHS) [published video] For Yourself: A Guide to Breast Self-Examination, produced by Memorial Sloan-Kettering Guttman Diagnostic Center, 1996 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-40 (VHS) Clinic Escort and Defense, by Bay Area Coalition Against Operation Rescue, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM V-41 (VHS) News clips, 3018 Anti-Abortion Polemic Introduced by Charlton Heston, Channel 55 (Long Island), early AM 10/29/1995 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-42 (VHS) Susan B. Anthony Awards; Diallo Street Arrests, by M. Jacquinot, 2000 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-43 (VHS) Pataki Demo, Channel 12 (Yonkers), 5/4/1996; Wall Street Demo; Abortion News Clips; Army of God; Funeral March for Matthew Shepard, 10/19/1998, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-44 (VHS) [published video] Like A Prayer, produced By DIVA TV (Damned Interfering Video Activist Television, c/o ACT UP, 1991 (Box 5)
- WHAM V-45 (VHS) Arrest at Board of Education, Youth Education Life Line (YELL), by Janet Wentzy, undated (Box 5)
- WHAM A-01 (Cassette) Clinic Defense Conference, Detroit Side A: Kass, from BACAOR (key note) Side B: BACAOR, Demonstration and dialogue on protecting door, March 23-24, 1990 (Box 5)
- WHAM A-02 (Micro) Skip [Robokoff?], Press Conference, April 19, 1990 (Box 5)
- WHAM A-03 (Micro) Elaine [Barthee?], 10:30 pm, May 5, 1990 (Box 5)
- WHAM A-04 (Micro) [Unlabeled], undated (Box 5)
- WHAM A-05 (Micro) Donald Grove, June 16, 1996 (Box 5)
- WHAM A-06 (Micro) [Elaine, anti-abortion activist?], undated (Box 5)
- WHAM A-07 (Cassette) Church Ladies for Choice Rehearsal, November 1, 1993 (Box 5)
- Subject Files, D-W (Stacy Mink donation), undated (Box 6)
- Early 1990s records (Elizabeth Meixell and Tracy Morgan donations), circa 1990-1995 (Box 7)
  Scope and Contents note
  This box includes committee minutes from 1990, materials related to Safe Sex 6 in 1991, materials related to Haiti and the Clinton transition in 1992, clippings, St. Patrick's legal documents, and checks.
- Early 1990s records (Meixell), circa 1990-1995 (Box 8)
  This box includes files from 1990, Church Ladies material from 1994, notebooks, slides, and materials related to the AIDS Cure Project in 1995 and the ACT UP Pataki Demonstration.
- Early 1990s records (Meixell donation?), circa 1990-1995 (Box 9)
  This box includes a photo album related to Statue of Liberty action, materials from the Clinic Defense Benefit in 1992, and general files from 1990.
- Early 1990s records (Meixell donation?), circa 1990-1995 (Box 10)
  This box includes files from 1990, clinic escort badges, WHAM Frontlines and ACT UP material, material realted to the ADAP Clinic Defense in 1993, and clippings.
- Early 1990s records (Meixell donation), circa 1990-1995 (Box 11)
  This box includes files from 1990 and St. Patrick's material.
- Early 1990s records, circa 1990-1995 (Box 12)
  This box includes files and clippings from 1992.
- Early 1990s records (Meixell and Erica Blitz donations?), circa 1990-1995 (Box 13)
  This box includes Frontlines material from 1992, Church Ladies/Clinic Defense materials from 1993, clippings, materials related to St. Patrick's action in 1995, and material on anti-abortion groups.
- Early 1990s records (Mink donation), circa 1990-1995 (Box 14)
  This box includes clippings from 1990-1991 and WHAM! posters
- Early 1990s records (Mink and Blitz donations?), circa 1990-1995 (Box 15)
  This box includes clinic escorter badges, general files from 1993-1994, materials related to the Women's Action Coalition and Clinic Defense, and the files of Erica Blitz, an urban herbalist.
- Treasurer's Records (Shannon Cain donation), undated (Box 16)
- Early 1990s records (Karen Ramspacher donation), circa 1990-1995 (Box 17)
- Clippings (Mink donation), undated (Box 18)
- Recent Files (Meixell donation), 1996-1997 (Box 19)
  This box includes materials related to Youth Education Life Line (YELL), Clinic Surveyor maps, and arrest records from an ACT UP Wall Street demonstration.
- Recent Files (Meixell donation), 1996-1997 (Box 20)
  This box includes binders on Clinic Defense and ACT UP 1996 materials.
- Recent Files (Meixell donation), 1998-2003 (Box 21)
  This box includes Fed Up Queers clippings and Church Ladies for Choice, anti-war, "corporate bureaucracy fans," and "WHAM has closed up shop" materials.
- Recent Files (Meixell donation), 1998-2003 (Box 22)
- Oversize Leaflets and original clippings for possible exhibit, undated (Box 23)
- No description, undated (Box 24)
- No description, undated (Box 25)
- Files pertaining to WHAM! and the New York Clinic Defense Task Force, which spun off from WHAM! in the run-up to the 1992 Democratic Convention., undated (Box 26)
- Marsha Clark donation (2012), 1990, 1993, 2001 (Box 27)
  Scope and Content Note
  This box contains a songbook from a Church Ladies for Choice concert in 2001, issues of pro-choice journal The Escorter and a small number of other publications, and flyers and organizing materials related to abortion advocacy, including opposition to pro-life organization Operation Rescue.
- Marsha Clark donation (2012), circa 1970-2000 (Box 28)
  This box contains a "Support the Equal Rights Amendment" t-shirt, two women's clinic escort aprons, and a t-shirt with "pro-choice" written in several different languages.
- "Microbicides" Banner (Meixell donation 2014), undated (Box 28)
- Political buttons (Clark donation 2012), circa 1970-2000 (Box 29)
- Meixell donation (2014), circa 2000-2007 (Box 29)
  This box includes signs from protests and other events, three posters on the topic of civil liberties, a "Nuns Having Fun" calendar, and a foam board cutout of a Susan B. Anthony coin given to Elizabeth Meixell by the Church Ladies for Choice.
- Meixell donation (2014), 1992-2010 (Box 30)
  This box mainly pertains to two distinct WHAM! campaigns: the Church Ladies for Choice group and WHAM!'s support of free vaginal microbicides as a form of HIV and STD prevention, particularly the Microbicide Development Act of 2003. These activities are documented in the form of Church Ladies song sheets; factsheets, form letters, reports, correspondence, and other work product of WHAM! and the WHAM! Microbicides Working Group; and news articles and fliers related to both campaigns. To a lesser extent, this box contains correspondence, surveys, and magazine drafts produced by the group Youth Education Life Line of ACT UP (YELL). Other assorted news articles, fliers, and correspondence concern various women's health issues, as well as causes not directly related to women's health. There are also a small number of photographs from various women's events.
- Meixell donation (2014), circa 2000-2010 (Box 31)
  This box contains posters and protest signs, mostly related to sexual health issues (namely AIDS and microbicides), though two posters have an anti-corporatism message.
- Meixell donation (2014), circa 1980-2010 (Box 32)
  This box contains WHAM! buttons and buttons for other women's and/or sexual health groups and causes, as well as four DVDs of a WHAM! forum that took place on October 15, 2005. This box also includes several artifacts: a pack of "Friendly Dictator" playing cards, a bar of soap with the message "Wash Your Ass!" (a tribute to civil and LGBT rights activist Bob Kohler), earrings in the form of "Family Planning" stamps, a keychain in the form of a pregnant woman.